http://www.rothschildarchive.org/archive/data_privacy_notice/

Welcome toThe Rothschild Archive'swebsite
Sources for business history: catalogues of bank files
Sources for art history: Catalogue of the pictures of Alfred de Rothschild 1901
Sources for yachting history: Plans for Nathaniel von Rothschild's yacht Veglia 1905
Sources for natural history: Walter 2nd Lord Rothschild and his zebra carriage: c.1910
Sources for global financial history: Map of lines of the Brazil Railway Company: c.1920
Sources for business history: index cards to bank files
Sources for social history: Rothschild Hospital Paris: 1920s
Sources for business history: detail of a Rothschild bond coupon
Sources for architectural history: Halton House: 1890s
Sources for the history of travel: Lionel de Rothschild's tours of Spain: 1909
Sources for local history: Tring Park: c.1900
Sources for Royal history: shooting party with Edward Prince of Wales: 1893
Sources for political history: Lionel de Rothschild: first Jewish MP: 1858
Sources for sporting history: St Amant winner of the Derby: 1904
Sources for local history: gardeners at Aston Clinton: 1899
Sources for Rothschild family history: Lionel de Rothschild's yacht Rhodora: 1927
Sources for London history: entrance to New Court: 1965
Sources for design history: plans for Lionel de Rothschild's Rolls-Royce: 1930
Sources for business history: Rothschild gold bars produced by the Royal Mint Refinery: 1930s
Sources for business history: letters of August Belmont Rothschild Agent in New York: 1860s
TheArchive
About UsThe Rothschild Archive TrustOur PoliciesRothschild Research ForumAnnual ReviewProjectsNewsSelect BibliographyArchive Research BursaryUseful LinksTerms and ConditionsData Privacy Notice
Data Privacy Notice
This page sets out the Data Privacy Notice of The Rothschild Archive Trust ('The Rothschild Archive').
The Rothschild Archive Trust ('The Rothschild Archive') is responsible for ensuring that it uses your personal data in compliance with data protection law. The purpose of this notice (the “Privacy Notice”) is to explain what personal data The Rothschild Archive collects and how The Rothschild Archive uses it. For the purposes of data protection law, The Rothschild Archive is a data controller in respect of your personal data. “Personal data” is any data that can be used to identify you or that The Rothschild Archive can link to you and which The Rothschild Archive has in its possession or control.
Personal data that The Rothschild Archive collects
The Rothschild Archive will collect and process the following personal data:
Information that you or someone acting on your behalf provides to The Rothschild Archive.
This includes information about you that you give The Rothschild Archive by filling in forms, signing up for services on our website or by communicating with The Rothschild Archive, whether face-to-face, by phone, e-mail or otherwise.
Information The Rothschild Archive collects or generates about you.
We will also collect information about you when you use our services or when we otherwise interact or correspond with you. We use various technologies to collect and store information when you visit our websites. We may, for example, collect information about the type of device you use to access the websites, your IP address and your geographic location, the operating system and version, your browser type, the content you view and features you access on our websites, the web pages and the search terms you enter on our websites. For information about how we use Cookies and the choices you may have, please see our Cookies Policy here.
Uses of your personal data
Personal data may be stored and processed by The Rothschild Archive in the following ways and for the following purposes:
to provide The Rothschild Archive’s services;
verify your identity (including for fraud prevention purposes), and to manage The Rothschild Archive’s relationship with you;
to contact you in connection with your enquiries and other services that The Rothschild Archive may provide to you;
to notify you about changes to The Rothschild Archive’s service; or
to comply with The Rothschild Archive’s legal and regulatory obligations.
The Rothschild Archive is entitled to use personal data in these ways because:
Consent – we may (but usually do not) need your consent to use your personal data. You can withdraw your consent by contacting us (see below).
Performance of a contract – we may need to collect and use your personal data to enter into a contract with you.
Legitimate interest – we may use your personal data for our legitimate interests, some examples of which are given above.
Compliance with law or regulation – we may use your personal data as necessary to comply with applicable law/regulation.
Disclosure of personal data to third parties
The Rothschild Archive may disclose personal data to third parties, as follows:
to provide the services or perform its obligations in connection with your contract;
for the management and administration of The Rothschild Archive business;
for the management and administration of internal policies and procedures within The Rothschild Archive;
to third party agents, service providers or contractors, bound by obligations of confidentiality, who will only use personal data on The Rothschild Archive’s behalf for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice;
to the extent required by law, regulation or court order for example if The Rothschild Archive is under a duty to disclose personal data in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation; and
in order to establish, exercise or defend The Rothschild Archive’s legal rights, for example if The Rothschild Archive needs to obtain external legal advice or provide personal data in connection with judicial proceedings.
Transfers of personal data outside the European Economic Area
Personal data may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”).
Where The Rothschild Archive transfers personal data outside the EEA, The Rothschild Archive will ensure that it is protected in a manner that is consistent with how personal data will be protected by The Rothschild Archive in the EEA. This may be achieved in one of the following ways:
the country that The Rothschild Archive sends the data to might be approved by the European Commission; or
the recipient might have signed a contract based on “model contractual clauses” approved by the European Commission, obliging them to protect the personal data that they receive; or
where the recipient is located in the US, it might be a certified member of the EU-US Privacy Shield scheme.
In other circumstances the law may permit The Rothschild Archive to otherwise transfer personal data outside the EEA. In all cases, however, The Rothschild Archive will ensure that any transfer of personal data is compliant with applicable data protection law.
You can obtain further details of the protection given to your personal data when it is transferred outside the EEA by contacting The Rothschild Archive in accordance with the “Contacting The Rothschild Archive” section below.
Retention of personal data
How long The Rothschild Archive holds personal data for will vary. The retention period will be determined by various criteria including:
the purpose for which The Rothschild Archive is using it – The Rothschild Archive will need to keep the data for as long as is necessary for that purpose; and
legal obligations – laws or regulation may set a minimum period for which The Rothschild Archive has to retain personal data.
Rights in relation to personal data
You have a number of legal rights in relation to the personal data that The Rothschild Archive holds about you. These rights include:
the right to obtain information regarding the processing of your personal data and access to the personal data which The Rothschild Archive holds about you;
the right to request that The Rothschild Archive rectify your personal data if it is inaccurate or incomplete;
the right to request that The Rothschild Archive erase your personal data in certain circumstances. Please note that there may be circumstances where you ask The Rothschild Archive to erase your personal data but The Rothschild Archive is legally entitled to retain it;
the right to object to, and the right to request that The Rothschild Archive restrict, its processing of your personal data in certain circumstances. Again, there may be circumstances where you object to, or ask The Rothschild Archive to restrict, its processing of your personal data but The Rothschild Archive is legally entitled to continue processing your personal data and / or to refuse that request;
in some circumstances, the right to receive some personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and/or request that The Rothschild Archive transmit such data to a third party where this is technically feasible. Please note that this right only applies to personal data which you have provided to The Rothschild Archive;
the right to withdraw your consent, although in certain circumstance it may be lawful for The Rothschild Archive to continue processing your data where The Rothschild Archive has another legitimate reason (other than consent) for doing so; and
the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant data protection authority if you think that any of your rights have been infringed by The Rothschild Archive.
You can exercise your rights by contacting The Rothschild Archive using the details set out in the “Contacting The Rothschild Archive” section below.
You can find out more information about your rights by contacting the relevant data protection authority. We can, on request, tell you which data protection authority is relevant to the processing of your personal data.
Contacting The Rothschild Archive
If you would like further information about The Rothschild Archive’s processing of your personal data or the exercise of any of the rights referred to above, please address questions, comments and requests to:
The Archivist,The Rothschild Archive,New Court,St Swithin’s Lane,LondonEC4N 8ALinfo@rothschildarchive.org
The ArchiveAbout UsDevelopment of the collectionsWhat does The Rothschild Archive London hold?The Rothschild Archive TrustOur PoliciesAccess PolicyCollecting PolicyCopying PolicyReading Room PolicyVolunteering PolicyRothschild Research ForumThe Rothschild GenealogyRothschild Family micrositesRothschild Business micrositeRothschild and Brazil micrositeRothschild Bonds micrositeRothschild Collections micrositeRothschilds and ScienceMy Dear Cousins: writing the new centuryAnnual ReviewReview of the Year: April 2013 - March 2014Review of the Year: April 2012 - March 2013Review of the Year: April 2011 - March 2012Review of the Year: April 2010 - March 2011Review of the Year: April 2009 - March 2010Review of the Year: April 2008 - March 2009Review of the Year: April 2007 - March 2008Review of the Year: April 2006 - March 2007Review of the Year: April 2005 - March 2006Review of the Year: April 2004 - March 2005Review of the Year: April 2003 - March 2004Review of the Year: April 2002 - March 2003Review of the Year: April 2001 - March 2002Review of the year: April 2000 - March 2001Review of the Year: April 1999 - March 2000ProjectsBullionRothschild Bonds'My Dear Cousins': writing the new centuryRothschild CollectionsRothschild BusinessThe 'Nathaniel 100' Transcription ProjectThe Rothschild GenealogyRothschild BiographiesRothschild EstatesGuide to the Collections of The Rothschild ArchiveRothschilds and ScienceRothschild and PhilanthropyRothschild and BrazilJudendeutsch LettersRothschild in CaricatureRothschild BibliographyThe Rothschild Research ForumNewsTreasure of the Month for December 2020EABH working papers series: latest publication: eabh paper 2020/03EABH working papers series: latest publication: eabh paper 2020/02Treasure of the Month for November 2020Treasure of the Month for October 2020Treasure of the Month for August 2020EABH working papers series: opportunity for new scholarsEABH Conference, 11 June 2020, Athens, GreeceEABH Workshop: Banking & the State, 23 February 2021, FrankfurtTreasure of the Month for July 2020Treasure of the Month for June 2020EABH Workshop: Banking & the State, 23 February 2021, Frankfurt - Final call for papersTreasure of the Month for May 2020EABH Workshop: Price Currents, Financial information and Market Transparency, 27 November 2020, Amsterdam, The NetherlandsTreasure of the Month for April 2020Treasure of the Month for March 2020Treasure of the Month for February 2020EABH Workshop: The Dynamics of Inclusive Finance, 20-21 March 2020: Call for PapersTreasure of the Month for January 2020EABH Conference, 26 October 2018, London, United KingdomTreasure of the Month for December 2019Treasure of the Month for September 2020Treasure of the Month for October 2019EABH Archival Workshop: Minting History, The Rothschild Archive London, 29 October 2019Bonds OnlineTreasure of the Month for September 2019Treasure of the Month for August 2019EABH Archival Workshop: Minting History, St Petersburg, 21 June 2019: Call for PapersTreasure of the Month for July 2019Treasure of the Month for June 2019Treasure of the Month for May 2019EABH Archival Workshop: GDPR and Historical Archives, European Central Bank, 23 March 2020Treasure of the Month for April 2019Treasure of the Month for March 2019Treasure of the Month for February 2019EABH Conference: The Development of Financial Markets, St Petersburg, 20 June 2019: Call for PapersEABH working papers series: latest publication: eabh paper 2020/04Treasure of the Month for January 2019Treasure of the Month for December 2018Treasure of the Month for November 2018Treasure of the Month for October 2018Treasure of the Month for September 2018Treasure of the Month for August 2018Treasure of the Month for November 2019Treasure of the Month for July 2018EABH Workshop, 10 November 2017, Zagreb, CroatiaTreasure of the Month for June 2018Treasure of the Month for May 2018Treasure of the Month for April 2018Treasure of the Month for March 2018Treasure of the Month for February 2018EABH Annual Meeting 2018: The Social Aims of FinanceTreasure of the Month for January 2018Treasure of the Month for December 2017Treasure of the Month for November 2017EABH Annual Meeting 2017: The Legacy of FinanceTreasure of the Month for October 2017Economic History Conference celebrating the 90th Anniversary of the Bank of GreeceTreasure of the Month for September 2017Treasure of the Month for August 2017EABH Conference: Money in Africa, Monetary and financial decolonisation in Africa, Lisbon, 9-10 October 2017EABH Research Associate Opportunity, Oxford UniversityFunding increased for Archive Research BursariesEABH Lunch Hour lecture, 'Populism and Financial Markets', Frankfurt am Main, 25 April 2017Reminder: Closure of the Archives Nationales du Monde du Travail, Roubaix, July 2017Treasure of the Month for May 2017Treasure of the Month for July 2017New Digital Archive of Rothschild bonds and prospectusesTreasure of the Month for June 2017Treasure of the Month for March 2017Treasure of the Month for February 2017Business Archives Council Bursary for business history researchEABH announces New Scholars Fast-Track Workshop: 13 June 2018, TorinoThe EABH publishes the latest contribution to its Working Papers SeriesClosure of the Archives Nationales du Monde du Travail, Roubaix, July 2017New Gallery: The Rothschild autochromesNew Gallery: Birthday testimonials of the first Lord Rothschild*NEW* Bullion microsite: a research resource for the study of Rothschild and goldTreasure of the Month for January 2017Treasure of the Month for December 2016Treasure of the Month for November 2016Launch of new microsite 'Rothschild Collections'Treasure of the Month for October 2016EABH Summer School 2016: Transparency & information management in financial institutionsTreasure of the Month for September 2016EABH Lunch Hour lecture, The rate of return on everything, Frankfurt am Main, 4 November 2016Treasure of the Month for August 2016EABH Conference: Innovative Solutions for Archives and Financial Crises, St Louis, 11-12 May 2017: Call for PapersTreasure of the Month for April 2017Treasure of the Month for June 2016EABH Annual Meeting 2016: '500 Years of Financial Interconnections. Did globalisation increase or decrease financial instability?', Vienna, Austria, 28-29 AprilTreasure of the Month for May 2016Treasure of the Month for April 2016Treasure of the Month for March 2016Recent Acquisitions: Expedition photographs of George Forrest, ChinaEABH Meeting: 'Origins of Banking Globalisation: The Experience of Spain and Latin America'Treasure of the Month for July 2016Treasure of the Month for February 2016Funding increased for Archive Research BursariesLaunch of new microsite 'My Dear Cousins'Treasure of the Month for January 2016Treasure of the Month for November 2015Treasure of the Month for October 2015Treasure of the Month for September 2015Treasure of the Month for August 2015EABH Oral History Project, Florence, Italy 28 Jan 2016Launch of new microsite 'Rothschild Business'EABH Annual Meeting 2015: 'History of Inflation. Inflation in History', Prague, 14-15 MayEABH Annual Meeting: ViennaRecent Acquisitions: Stamps, punches and dies from The Royal Mint RefineryRecent Acquisitions: Yacht gavel from TSY AtmahTreasure of the Month for July 2015Treasure of the Month for June 2015Treasure of the Month for May 2015A Rothschild Renaissance: Treasures from the Waddesdon BequestRefurbished Rothschild Room, the Natural History Museum at TringTreasure of the Month for December 2015Recent Acquisitions: 'Luthmer' CataloguesTreasure of the Month for March 2015Recent Acquisitions: Estate ledgers and account books account books from the Château de FerrièresRestoring a Legacy: Rothschild Family Treasures: Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Massachusetts: March-June 2015EABH Annual Meeting 2016: '500 Years of Financial Interconnections. Did globalisation increase or decrease financial instability?', Vienna, Austria, 28-29 AprilJewish Nursing HistoryEABH Conference 2015: 'Historical links betwen USA and Spain', Madrid, 9-11 AprilTreasure of the Month for April 2015The Royal Mint revives The Royal Mint Refinery brandImages of the Frankfurt JudengasseTreasure of the Month for January 2015Treasure of the Month for December 2014Release of Bank of England Court MinutesWaterloo 200PhD studentship in Financial History: University of GlasgowTreasure of the Month for November 2014Recent Acquisitions: A Rothschild PortraitTreasure of the Month for October 2014Treasure of the Month for February 2015Yerusha: Archives in EuropeRecent Acquisitions: The Rothschild Reserves ArchiveRecent Acquisitions: 'the book that started it all'Treasure of the Month for August 2014Recent Acquisitions: Papers concerning orchid cultivationRecent Acquisitions: Mr Warren's Photograph AlbumTreasure of the Month for September 2014Treasure of the Month for July 2014Treasure of the Month for June 2014Recent Acquisitions: Quill pensTreasure of the Month for May 2014Select BibliographyArchive Research BursaryUseful LinksThe American Museum of Natural HistoryArchives nationales du monde du travail (ANMT)Arolsen ArchivesBank for International SettlementsBalfour 100Bank of England ArchiveBarclays Group ArchivesThe Baring ArchiveBrady Street cemetery, London: Rothschild gravesThe British Library Department of ManuscriptsThe British Museum: The Waddesdon BequestBuda Pesth Chain Bridge Archive RecordsThe Butrint FoundationThe Business Archives CouncilCentral Zionist ArchivesChâteau Mouton Rothschild: wine labelsCultural plunder: database of art objects at the Jeu de PaumeThe Ephrussi family archiveThe Eranda FoundationThe European Association for Banking and Financial History e.V.Exbury GardensFondation de RothschildGoethe University Frankfurt: Rothschild Library FrankfurtGunnersbury Park MuseumHalton HouseHanne Wassermann ArchiveThe Hartley Library, University of SouthamptonHidden Treasures: Celebrating Jewish Archives in BritainHistoric England ArchiveIndustrial Dwellings SocietyInstitut national d'histoire de l'artJacqueline PiatigorskyThe Jewish Museum, FrankfurtJewish Nursing HistoryJoram PiatigorskyThe Kitchener CollectionMiriam Rothschild and John Foster Human Rights TrustÖsterreichische Nationalbibliothek, Vienna, Digital Library & CataloguePalace House: The National Heritage Centre for Horseracing & Sporting ArtPicpus, Walled Garden of Memory: Digital ArchivePhoto Seed: early fine-art photographyProject HOCT: History of Tea in CeylonThe National ArchivesThe National TrustThe Natural History Museum, TringRamat HanadivThe Rosebery EstatesThe Rothschild Foundation (Hanadiv) EuropeThe Royal Institute of British ArchitectsThe Royal MintThe Wiener Holocaust LibrarySculpt the Future FoundationSpanish Railways FoundationStadt-und Universitatsbibliothek, Frankfurt am MainVilla & Jardins Ehprussi de RothschildWaddesdon ManorWaterloo 200The Wildlife TrustsWitkowitz IronworksWorld Jewish Relief ArchivesYerusha: Jewish Archives in EuropeTerms and ConditionsData Privacy NoticeThe CollectionsCustodial history of the CollectionsBusiness Collections (London)Business Collections (France)Family PapersRothschild estatesProvenance researchSources for Jewish studiesPhotograph CollectionsTreasure of the MonthDecember 2020: Checkmate! Jacqueline Piatigorsky chess photographs, c.1960November 2020: Obsolete technology, c.1995-2005October 2020: Portrait of Louise, Baroness Mayer Carl von Rothschild and her daughter Adele, c.1844September 2020: Portrait plaques of Carl Mayer and Adelheid von Rothschild, c.1840August 2020: Self-portrait of Charlotte, Baroness Anselm von Rothschild, with her husband, two of their children, and their nanny, 1838July 2020: The Baroness de Koenigswarter Jazz Musicians Photograph Collection, c.1954-1985June 2020: Silk scarf commemorating the Grand Prix de Paris, won by Crudité, 1935May 2020: Making history: the ‘Familien Archiv Register’ of Salomon von Rothschild, 1844April 2020: Walther Straram’s ‘business plan’, c.1918March 2020: ‘Ancient Cheques’, 1813-1864February 2020: ‘The Mentmore Dresser’, c.1840January 2020: Wooden box of precious metal samples, c.1860December 2019: Edward The VII ‘Coronation’ Silver and gold coin set, 1902November 2019: Miniature of Evelina de Rothschild, c.1865October 2019: Letters Patent of Denization for Nathan Mayer Rothschild, 1804September 2019: Flag from the Gold Fixing Room, New Court, 2004August 2019: Mr Eddy’s ‘stage’ in America, 1947July 2019: Portrait photographs, The Devonshire House Ball, 1897June 2019: Fondation Rothschild Paris, designs for social housing, 1905-1906May 2019: Manchester Ship Canal Company Prospectus issued by N M Rothschild & Sons, 1886April 2019: Queen Mary Inaugural Coasting Cruise souvenirs, 1936March 2019: Royal Horticultural Society awards, Exbury estate, 1930-1953February 2019: Telegraphic code books (South American business), 1909-1938January 2019: Photogravure study ‘Waidhoffener Ninetta', 1891December 2018: 'Season's Greetings', seasonal cards, 1897-1997November 2018: Croix de Guerre, Robert de Rothschild (1880-1946), 1918October 2018: "The land that never was": correspondence between Gregor MacGregor and N M Rothschild, 1821September 2018: "The Season in the South of France", The Graphic, 1892August 2018: Portrait of a ‘Princess’: Bertha Clara von Rothschild by Ellis William Roberts, 1890July 2018: Judendeutsch letter, James to Nathan, concerning the apprenticeship of Nathaniel Rothschild, June 1831June 2018: Medal awarded at the Halton & Aston Clinton Industrial Exhibition, 1868May 2018: Gunnersbury Park sales particulars, 1835April 2018: Letter from Ernest Shackleton, 1914March 2018: Subscription ledger for the Prussian Government loan, 1818February 2018: Letters of Introduction, Valparaíso, Chile, 1848January 2018: Photograph of Liliane de Rothschild skiing, c.1935December 2017: East India Company stock list, 1815November 2017: Uniform regalia of Evelyn Achille de Rothschild, c.1915October 2017: Thank-you letter from Robert Baden Powell to Lord Rothschild, 1915September 2017: Jewellery designs by Maurice Tripier for Baroness Adelheid de Rothschild, c.1925August 2017: David Samuel von Madai's catalogue of coins, 1788July 2017: Receipts for tennis, 1856 and 1915June 2017: Brazilian bond and scrip, 1824May 2017: Penant and programmes of the Vienna Football Club, c.1960April 2017: Cinquantenaire de la Compagnie Internationale des Wagon-lits & des Grands Express EuropéensMarch 2017: The Rothschild AutochromesFebruary 2017: Plan of the Rothschild saltworks, Venice, c.1860January 2017: The New Court Shield, c.1865December 2016: ‘Livre des comptes de cuisine’ (Kitchen Account Book), 1833November 2016: Presidential 'Thank you' note, 1904October 2016: Staff wages file, 1874-1915September 2016: Armstrong Siddeley Motors sales catalogue, 1936August 2016: Acquisition of the Witkowitz Ironworks, 1842July 2016: Ferdinand de Rothschild's 'Red Book', 1897June 2016: Jockey's cap in the Rothschild colours, c.1935May 2016: Letter from August Belmont, 1837April 2016: Badge of office, the Alliance Assurance Company, 1825March 2016: Nathan Mayer Rothschild's bill-case, 1831February 2016: Portrait of Rozsika Rothschild, c.1910January 2016: Japanese New Year card, 1909December 2015: Programme from the St Swithin's Musical Society concert season, 1899November 2015: Panorama of the funeral procession of the Duke of Wellington, 1852October 2015: Portrait of Hannah Rothschild, 1825September 2015: New Court and the London Blitz, 1941August 2015: Mr Stephany's business trip to Spain, 1925July 2015: Death mask of Nathan Mayer Rothschild, 1836June 2015: Phrenology reports, 1849May 2015: Election pledge card, 1922April 2015: 'Titanic' letter, 1912March 2015: Suez Canal loan receipts, 1876February 2015: Royal Mint Refinery papers, 1852January 2015: Halton House album, 1884December 2014: Christmas gift books, 1909, 1912 and 1931November 2014: Letters from The Front, 1914-1918October 2014: Trade report from Italy, 1828September 2014: The 'Warburg' letter, 1926August 2014: 'Lord Rothschild's Maxims', 1911July 2014: the wedding of Leopold and Marie, 1881June 2014: Nathan Rothschild's 'Cotton Book', 1801-1804May 2014: Chinese Sycees, 1901 and 1903Collections ElsewhereRecent AcquisitionsPhotograph by Salomon Albert Anselm von Rothschild: 'Waidhoffener Ninetta'Catalogue of 'Old Master' pictures of Alfred de Rothschild'Schiffsbilder' an album of heliogravure photographsExpedition photographs of George Forrest, China, c.1919Estate ledgers and account books from the Château de FerrièresMap and postcards of The Grand Trunk Railway, CanadaMetal stamps, punches and dies from the Royal Mint RefineryRock crystal seal of Anselm Salomon von RothschildGavel from the 'TSY Atmah''Luthmer' CataloguesImages of the Frankfurt Judengasse'The book that started it all': papers from the estate of Bettina LooramA Rothschild PortraitThe Rothschild Reserves ArchiveQuill pensPapers concerning orchid cultivationMr Warren's Photograph AlbumThe FamilyRothschild Name & ArmsRed Shield and Green ShieldThe Rothschild Coat of ArmsFive ArrowsRothschild, de Rothschild, von RothschildRothschild GenealogyFamily biographiesFamily estatesFamily bibliographyFamily interestsAgriculture & conservationDanceFilmFood & drinkFreemasonryHorseracingHorticulture & gardensLiteratureMotoringMusicPaintingPhotographyPoliticsScience & medicineSculptureSportTheatreTravelWineYachtingZoology & botanyFamily collectionsLe Goût RothschildArms & armourAutographsBooks & manuscriptsChinese porcelainCigarsCoinsCostume, buttons & braidsDrawings & engravingsGold & silver art objectsJewelleryJudaicaNatural historyPaintingsReligious objets d'artSchatzkammer & kunstkammern objectsSèvresSnuff boxesPhilanthropyCharitable donations, 1902Arts, culture & librariesEducationHealthSocial welfareJewish causesBaron Edmond de Rothschild & PalestineFamily FoundationsThe BusinessOrigins of the businessA family partnershipM A Rothschild and M A von Rothschild & Söhne, FrankfurtN M Rothschild & Sons, LondonNathan Mayer Rothschild and 'Waterloo'Rothschild and goldLionel de Rothschild and the Suez Canalde Rothschild Frères, ParisS M von Rothschild, ViennaC M de Rothschild & Figli, NaplesRothschilds who directed the businessRothschilds directing the Frankfurt HouseRothschilds directing the London HouseRothschilds directing the Paris HouseRothschilds directing the Vienna HouseRothschilds directing the Naples HouseBusiness premisesThe Frankfurt banking house: 146, FahrgasseThe London banking house: New Court, St Swithin's LaneThe Vienna banking house: the Römischer Kaiser, RenngasseThe Paris banking house: 19, rue LaffitteThe Naples banking house: the Villa Acton-Pignatelli, Riviera di ChiaiaBusiness employeesPrivate clientsThe Royal Mint RefineryThe RMR: early years 1852-1914The RMR: business 1914-1968Revival of the 'Royal Mint Refinery' brandThe Alliance Assurance CompanyHistory of 'The Alliance'Rothschilds and 'The Alliance'Rothschild worldwideBusiness activitiesGroup Edmond de RothschildWine businesses'Rothschild' tea and coffeeExhibitionsRothschild TimelineThe first identified Rothschild ancestor in FrankfurtHouse of the 'Red Shield' built in FrankfurtFirst evidence of the name 'Rothschild' in recordsMayer Amschel Rothschild born in FrankfurtMayer Amschel Rothschild apprenticed at Oppenheimer BankMayer Amschel Rothschild becomes Court Agent to the Principality of Hesse-HanauBirth of Amschel Mayer RothschildBirth of Salomon Mayer RothschildBirth of Nathan Mayer RothschildRothschild family move into the 'House of the Green Shield'Birth of Carl Mayer RothschildBirth of James RothschildThe first Rothschild family partnershipNathan Rothschild leaves Frankfurt for ManchesterMayer Amschel Rothschild granted title of Imperial Crown AgentThe first Rothschild client: The Elector of Hesse CasselRothschilds first deal in bullionJames Rothschild joins the family PartnershipN M Rothschild established in LondonAmschel Mayer Rothschild assumes control of the Frankfurt houseJames de Rothschild establishes de Rothschild FrèresThe Rothschilds supply gold to WellingtonNews of the English victory at Waterloo reaches New CourtFirst major loan business: the Prussian Government 5% LoanSalomon Rothschild arranges loans to Prince MetternichCarl Rothschild sets up in NaplesThe Rothschild brothers are made BaronsBankers to Brazil: the Brazilian 5% LoanAlliance Assurance Company foundedRothschilds save the Bank of EnglandN M Rothschild appointed Bankers to the United States in EuropeRothschilds begin their involvement with AlmadénDeath of Nathan Mayer Rothschild: Lionel Nathan de Rothschild leads the London houseEarliest Rothschild trade with ChinaSalomon von Rothschild builds Austria's first railwayRothschild cousins and Ceylon teaSalomon Rothschild buys the Witkowitz (Vítkovice) ironworksde Rothschild Frères finances the Nord lineRothschilds raise Irish famine relief fundsAnslem Salomon von Rothschild takes over the Viennese houseGold in California: establishment of a Rothschild agency in San FranciscoThe London bank uses the new communcations services of ReutersMayer Rothschild builds Mentmore TowersFoundation of the Hôpital Fondation de Rothschild, ParisAdvisers to RoyaltyAcquisition of the San Rafael IronworksEstablishment of the Royal Mint RefineryJames de Rothschild builds Château de FerrièresNathaniel de Rothschild buys Château Brane MoutonMayer Carl and Wilhelm Carl become joint partners in the Frankfurt houseThe American Banking CrisisAdolphe de Rothschild builds Château de PregnyLionel de Rothschild takes his seat in ParliamentFirst rebuilding of New CourtClosure of the Naples businessJames de Rothschild buys Château LafiteAlphonse de Rothschild assumes control of the Paris houseOpening of the Evelina Hospital, LondonAlfred de Rothschild appointed as a Director of the Bank of EnglandFoundation of the Hôpital Rothschild, Berck Plage-sur-mer'The Baron's Year': pre-eminence on the turfThe first Channel Tunnel project beginsThe Rothschilds become shareholders in Rio TintoSalomon Albert Anselm takes over the Viennese houseFoundation of the Clementine Hospital, FrankfurtN M Rothschild & Sons funds the Suez purchaseNathaniel Mayer Rothschild becomes Senior PartnerThe French Rothschilds co-found the mining company, PeñarroyaThe Bengal and North Western Railway LoanThe French Rothschilds establish the mining company, Société Le NickelFerdinand de Rothschild entertains at Waddesdon ManorNathaniel Rothschild created the first Jewish peerCreation of the Four Percent Industrial Dwellings Company LtdFormation of The Exploration CompanyN M Rothschild & Sons arrange finance for the Manchester Ship Canalde Rothschild Frères develops interests in Russian oilRothschilds finance the establishment of De BeersBurma Ruby Mines Limited share issueWalter, 2nd Lord Rothschild creates his natural history museumThe Baring CrisisSouth African Republic (Transvaal) 5% Loan for public worksNathaniel von Rothschild credited with introducing the sport of football to AustriaBurma Railway LoanThe Pekin SyndicateEstablishment of the Rhodes ScholarshipsClosure of the Frankfurt BankAn 'entertaining' client listSt Amant wins the DerbyBéatrice Ephrussi builds the villa Ile-de-FranceEdouard Alphonse de Rothschild takes control of de Rothschild FrèresThe Fondation Opthalmologique Adolphe de Rothschild opens in ParisLionel de Rothschild wins 'La perla del Mediterraneo’Loans to JapanBirth of Miriam RothschildLionel de Rothschild experiments with autochromesBirth of Victor, 3rd Lord RothschildLord Rothschild declines to insure The 'Titanic'The three Rothschild sons manage the Vienna bankThe Society for the Promotion of Nature Reserves surveyThe Aston Clinton Hill ClimbNew Court and the First World WarAlfred de Rothschild becomes Senior PartnerThe Balfour DeclarationEvelyn de Rothschild and Anthony de Rothschild become PartnersCharles Rothschild, scientist and organiser, becomes Senior PartnerThe first Gold Fixing takes place at New CourtLionel Nathan de Rothschild becomes Senior PartnerBaron Edmond de Rothschild establishes the Palestine Jewish Colonization AssociationRothschild philanthropy in FrankfurtGunnersbury Estate becomes a public parkEconomic reconstruction in Europe: Hungarian bondsN M Rothschild & Sons finances expansion of London's Underground railwaysHenri de Rothschild opens the Theatre PigalleN M Rothschild & Sons respond to the Creditanstalt crisisSupport for Jewish refugeesThe fabulous Rothschild Hispano-SuizasLionel de Rothschild and The Roads Beautifying AssociationMr Eddy's Round-the-World tourN M Rothschild & Sons and the nationalisation of the French railwaysThe Rothschilds leave ViennaThe Royal Mint Refinery helps the war effortMembers of the French family leave France on 'Mendes' visasNew Court survives the blitzAnthony Gustav de Rothschild becomes Senior PartnerRothschilds in the United StatesChâteau Mouton 'Victory Year' wine labelThe French Rothschilds acquire Paris OrléansEdmund de Rothschild becomes a PartnerBusiness resumes with JapanGuy de Rothschild becomes head of the French bankGuy de Rothschild becomes president of the Compagnie du Chemin de Fer NordRothschilds finance development of natural resources in Newfoundland and LabradorN M Rothschild & Sons establishes the Merchant Bank of Central AfricaLeopold de Rothschild becomes a PartnerJames and Dorothy de Rothschild give Waddesdon Manor to the nationDorothy de Rothschild establishes Yad HanadivN M Rothschild & Sons sets up its first unit trustEvelyn de Rothschild becomes a PartnerEdmund de Rothschild becomes Senior Partner of the London houseN M Rothschild & Sons: first non-Rothschild partner appointedRothschilds and ChileEdmond de Rothschild forms La Compagnie FinancièreJacob Rothschild becomes a PartnerRothschild returns to ManchesterThe London bank occupies new officesThe Knesset ceremony of dedication takes placeSale of the Royal Mint RefineryCreation of Banque Rothschild; rebuilding of the French bank officesN M Rothschild & Sons finance the Rio de Janeiro-Niteroi BridgeCreation of Rothschild Bank AGN M Rothschild & Sons becomes a limited companyN M Rothschild & Sons first involvement in privatisationN M Rothschild & Sons Limited advise Rolls-RoyceMr Edmund de Rothschild awarded the Japanese Order of the Sacred TreasureRothschild Asset Management Limited is establishedN M Rothschild & Sons Limited finance railways in Hong KongBanque Rothschild establishes ImétalVictor, 3rd Lord Rothschild becomes ChairmanN M Rothschild & Sons advise on developmental projects in ChinaEvelyn de Rothschild becomes Chairman of N M Rothschild & Sons LimitedJacob Rothschild establishes RITNationalisation of the French bankRelaunch of Rothschild's French activities through Paris OrléansPrivatisation of British TelecomRothschild advise on the flotation of ReutersPrivatisation of British GasCreation of Rothschild & CieSale of British PetroleumRothschild appointed financial adviser to the Cardiff Bay Development CorporationPrivatisation of British SteelRothschild banking returns to FrankfurtWater company privatisationElectricity privatisationN M Rothschild & Sons Limited opens Denver officeInauguration of the new Supreme Court building, IsraelN M Rothschild & Sons Limited advise on the restructuring of the British railway industryRothschild reopened the dormant Eurosterling convertible bond marketRothschild advises Peel Holdings on the acquistion of shares in The Manchester Ship Canal CompanyCreation of 'The Rothschild Collection' of historic gold and silver bars by N M Rothschild & Sons (Australia)Sale of British CoalMemorandum of Understanding with the Industrial and Commercial Bank of ChinaRothschild forms a joint venture with ABM AMRORothschild appointed by HM Prison Service to advise on financing of new prisonsRothschild Australia Limited begins to trade as a bankN M Rothschild & Sons Limited develop 3G licence auctionsRothschild becomes the leading adviser on UK takeovers worth less than £250 millionN M Rothschild & Sons: 'Bank of the Year'Unification of the French and English Rothschild businessesDavid de Rothschild becomes Rothschild Group ChairmanEnd of the Gold Fixing at New CourtFourth rebuilding of New CourtThe 'Plastiki' crosses the PacificRothschild advise Zhejiang Geely on the acquisition of Volvo Car CorporationDomaines Barons de Rothschild develops its first Chinese vineyardBicentenary of the arrival of James de Rothschild in ParisNew Court shortlisted for the 2012 RIBA Stirling PrizeRothschild advise Network RailRothschild advise on the sale of the 'Financial Times'Paris Orléans becomes Rothschild & CoAriane de Rothschild appointed CEO, Edmond de Rothschild GroupRothschild & Co establishes Chicago officeRothschild & Co completes merger with Compagnie Financière Martin MaurelRothschild & Co opens a new wholly owned subsidiary in TokyoRothschild & Co opens a San Francisco Bay Area officeRothschild & Co advises Notting Hill Housing on £400m bond issueAlexandre de Rothschild becomes chairman of Rothschild & CoRothschild & Co advises on the sale of Wembley StadiumThe Rothschild family sell their last link with Austria after 200 YearsRothschild & Co provides debt advice to The All England Lawn Tennis Ground on its £200m bank refinancingRothschild AutochromesThe colours of another ageLionel de Rothschild: autochrome pioneerAutochrome Gallery'If you see Sid...Tell him!'The privatisation of British Gas, 1986The origins of British GasPrivatisationThe legacyFaith & CharityEarly support for Jewish causesA broad commitment to welfareA legacy of givingCharitable donations of the familyNathaniel, 1st Lord RothschildThe 70th Birthday testimonials to Nathaniel, 1st Lord RothschildTestimonial from the Jews' Free SchoolTestimonial from the London Committee of the Deputies of British JewsTestimonial from the Board of Guardians for the Relief of the Jewish PoorTestimonial to Lord & Lady Rothschild from the Jewish Association for the Protection of Women and GirlsTestimonial from staff of the Tring EstateTestimonial from the 'inhabitants of Tring'Testimonial from the Council of the United SynagogueTestimonial from the Board of Management of the Great SynagogueGallery of testimonialsFamily Philanthropy todayRothschild GardensRothschild gardensCreating the visionGunnersbury Park, west LondonAston Clinton, BuckinghamshireHalton, BuckinghamshireAscott, BuckinghamshireExbury, HampshireAshton Wold, NorthamptonshireWaddesdon Manor, BuckinghamshireChâteau de Boulogne, Boulogne-sur-SeineIle de France, Cap FerratSchillersdorf, MoraviaPregny, SwitzerlandVilla Victoria, GrasseRamat Hanadiv, IsraelRothschilds and the plant huntersRothschild Flora: species and cultivarsRothschilds and the First World WarRothschilds and the First World WarBusiness during the warThe Jewish War Services CommitteeRothschilds on active serviceLetters homeThe home frontHalton House at WarThe New Court War MemorialFrom Bank to WestminsterLionel de Rothschild's journey to parliament, 1847-1858From the Frankfurt ghettoNathan Rothschild founds a bank in the City of LondonLionel takes over the businessNathan Mayer Rothschild and Jewish emancipationLionel stands for parliamentLionel's political manifestoLionel is elected to parliament for the City of LondonThe oath for Christians onlyLionel resigns and stands againLionel tries to take his seatThe House of Lords refuses to change the oathAnother Jew is elected to parliamentDisraeli solves the problemLionel takes his seatNathaniel de Rothschild becomes the first Jewish peerMotoring RothschildsLionel de Rothschild: motoring pioneerMotoring in SpainEarly motoring in FranceMiss Alice's double landauLionel de Rothschild, Wolseley and Rolls-RoyceMotor sport: the Aston Hill ClimbThe Roads Beautifying AssociationThe Rothschild Hispano-SuizasVictor Rothschild's Bugatti AtlanticMotor racing and the RothschildsHorse Racing RothschildsEarly involvement in horse racingHannahLeopold de Rothschild 1845-1917Leo's failures and successesSt. AmantFrench RothschildsLegal agreementsHorse racing in AustriaRothschilds and BrazilThe Rothschilds in BrazilFinancing the new nationRailwaysHenry Lynch (1878-1958)CoffeeBrazil Centennial International ExhibitionThe Art of Natural HistoryWalter Rothschild and his Museum at TringNovitates ZoologicaeArtistic correspondenceCharles RothschildDame Miriam RothschildMaurice de RothschildRothschilds in CaricatureIntroductionA View from the Royal ExchangeThe Beauties of Brighton'Die Generalpumpe'Frankfurt Revolt, 1848FerrièresLionel de Rothschild, Gillot 1870Feeding timeA view from AmericaMusee des HorreursA quiet evening in Seamore PlaceLloyd GeorgeThe Cresus'sSeason's GreetingsSir Henry Cole begins a tradition1897 New Year card sent to Mrs Leopold de Rothschild1904 Postcard with New Year wishes sent to Baron Edmond de Rothschild1904 Christmas card sent to Leopold de Rothschild1909 Japanese New Year card sent to Nathaniel, 1st Lord Rothschild1917 Christmas card sent to Mrs Leopold de Rothschild by the 56th (London) Infantry Division1956 Personal Christmas card sent by Victor Rothschild1958 Seasonal card sent by N M Rothschild & Sons1973 Seasonal message sent from N M Rothschild & Sons Limited1975 Seasonal card sent from Château Mouton1977 Personal card sent to Victor, 3rd Lord Rothschild1987 Seasonal card sent from Château Lafite1988 Seasonal card sent from N M Rothschild & Sons Limited1990 Seasonal card sent from Rothschild Bank Zurich1991 Christmas and New Year card sent to Mr Leopold de Rothschild1994 Corporate card sent by N M Rothschild & Sons Limited1997 Seasonal card sent by Rothschild AustraliaCelebrating our Jewish collectionsSilver menorah, c.1800-1805Letters Patent of Denization for Nathan Mayer Rothschild, 1804Letter in Judendeutsch from Nathan Mayer Rothschild to his brothers, 1816Badge of office of the Alliance British and Foreign Life and Fire Assurance Company, 1824The ‘Poll book’, 1847The ‘Disdéri' photograph album, 1859-1863Commemorative album for the marriage of Leopold de Rothschild to Marie Perugia, 1881Prospectus for shares in the Four per cent Industrial Dwellings Company, 1885Presentation Key to Brondesbury Synagogue, 1905Lord Rothschild’s 70th birthday testimonial from the Jews’ Free School, London, 1910Minute Book of the proceedings of The Jewish War Services Committee, 1915-1918Contact UsEnquiriesVisiting UsAccess to collections held in LondonAccess to collections held in Roubaix, FranceCopying of documentsCitation GuidelinesFAQsOrigins of the Rothschild family businessRothschild philanthropyAm I a Rothschild?Red Shield and Green ShieldRothschild, de Rothschild, von RothschildFive ArrowsNathan Mayer Rothschild and 'Waterloo'Rothschilds and pigeon postOld Rothschild BondsRothschild and goldLionel de Rothschild and the Suez CanalBusiness employeesRothschild Estate recordsRothschild art and object collectionsThe Rothschild AutochromesRothschild gardensWalter Rothschild and the Balfour DeclarationRothschilds in politicsBaron Edmond de Rothschild & PalestineRothschild and WineRothschilds and the natural worldRothschilds and horseracingA history of New Court
